Hello, I'm Daniel. I'll
tell you about a small project
of mine that I'm
starting up, Technology Enhanced
Learning Studies. The name
is a combination of two
fields. It's the first
one being Technology Enhanced
Learning, which provides
a synchronous yet interactive
learning material which is reusable
and particularly
reproducible when it comes
to studying it.
And this lends itself
nicely to to the second half,
which is Learning
Studies. And this is a research
methodology developed by Ference Marton at Gothenburg
University. It consists
of combining the variation
theory of learning
with design based research,
which is an iterative
research methodology
to improve
something like teaching.
And the idea is
to combine these two
because they provide
nice properties, particularly
the reproducibility
and scalability.
And the idea is to create
teaching material
for introductory
programming, which is well
founded in pedagogy and didactic
research. However,
the impact for KTH
is, of course, I'll apply this
in my introductory
programming courses. I have
a bit more than 300
students per year and different types
of students, which is good
for studying the effect
of the teaching. It covers three programs.
I also ... all of which are non-CS majors.
I recruit TAs from the CL
program, which is nice
because they are well
versed in other theories
of learning so they are equipped with
research methodology
for studying learning,
but they will also learn
and practice this methodology,
which is not
included in their program.
And lastly, they also
get teaching material
which they have
helped develop and research
which is open to use,
because it's open under a Creative
Commons license.
However, it also impacts society
because we will open
this teaching for schools,
because this
teaching is available by design
and the schools must
teach programming and the maths
classes starting already
in the first year. However,
our material is relevant
from seventh grade
and onwards. These CL TAs
will eventually move
to schools where they can
continue to contribute
and study this
material and improving it.
And the schools, the teachers
who
haven't taken the CL
program, they can
contribute anyway as
well, which is nice because then
they get into this
research practice, which can benefit
improving teaching
in other subjects and other
classes that they teach. And
that was it. Thanks a lot.